In the last lesson we looked at some of the common terms used in version control systems.
اطلعنا في الدرس السابق على بعض المصطلحات الشائعة المُستخدمة في أنظمة التحكم في الإصدار.
You also install GIT on your computer and did
يمكنك أيضا تثبيت GIT على جهاز الكمبيوتر
some initial configuration of GIT like adding your name and email.
كما قمت ببعض التكوين الأولي لـ GIT كإضافة اسمك وبريدك الإلكتروني.
If you skip these steps it's probably
إذا كنت تتخطى هذه الخطوات، فربما تكون فكرة جيدة
a good idea to go back and check them out again before continuing.
للرجوع إليها والتحقق منها مرة أخرى قبل المتابعة.
In this lesson we'll be learning how to create our own GIT repositories.
في هذا الدرس، سنتعلم كيفية إنشاءGIT repositories الخاصة بنا.
I mean we can't really do anything without having a repo to work with.
أعني أننا لا يمكن أن نفعل أي شيء حقًا دون وجود مستودع لاستخدامه في العمل.
Oh and "repo" is just short for repository,
مع ملاحظة أن "repo" هي اختصار "repository"،
does mean exactly the same thing,
يعني بالضبط الشيء نفسه،
so I'll be using them interchangeably.
لذلك سأستخدمها بالتبادل.
Remember to keep the list of terms nearby as a reference.
تذكر الاحتفاظ بقائمة المصطلحات القريبة كمرجع.
We'll be looking at three GIT commands in this lesson.
وفي هذا الدرس، سنطلع على أوامر GIT الثلاثة.
GIT init, GIT clone and GIT status.
GIT init وGIT clone وGIT status.
With GIT init, you'll create brand new repositories from scratch on your computer.
من خلال GIT init، ستقوم بإنشاء مستودعات جديدة من البداية على جهاز الكمبيوتر.
With GIT clone, you'll clone or copy
ومن خلال GIT clon، ستتعلم استنساخ أو نسخ
an existing repo from somewhere else to your local computer.
مستودع موجود بالفعل من مكان آخر إلى جهازك الكمبيوتر.
You'll also learn how vitally important it is to know the status of a repo.
كما ستتعلم مدى أهمية معرفة حالة المستودع.
You'll learn to check the status of a repo with the GIT status command.
ستتعلم التحقق من حالة المستودع من خلال الأمر GIT status.
Three simple commands but they're starting us
ثلاثة أوامر بسيطة لكنها تمثل نقطة بداية
on our journey towards version control mastery.
في رحلتنا نحو التحكم في الإصدار.
Let's get going with GIT init.
دعونا نبدأ باستعراض GIT init.